<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybersecurity on faultint</title>
    <link>/en/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cybersecurity on faultint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 18:42:50 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/en/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire Bandit 5</title>
      <link>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 18:42:50 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-5/</guid>
      <description>This is level 4 -&amp;gt; level 5 of bandit wargame from overthewire.
Password stored in a file somewhere on the server. Here is the goal level.
The password for the next level is stored in the only human-readable file in the inhere directory. Tip: if your terminal is messed up, try the “reset” command.
So logged in to the game server. Change directory to inhere. You will find a lot of files with similar names that has increasing number at the end of its name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire Bandit 4</title>
      <link>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 18:33:27 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-4/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with level 3 -&amp;gt; level 4. The password is stored in a file, somewhere on the server.
Here is the level goal.
The password for the next level is stored in a hidden file in the inhere directory.
Hidden file is a file named beginning with dot. It won&amp;rsquo;t be displayed using ls command. You need to add -a flag to display hidden file. Naming directory beginning with dot will also makes it hidden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire Bandit 3</title>
      <link>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 19:04:51 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-3/</guid>
      <description>This is level 2 -&amp;gt; level 3 in the bandit wargame from overthewire.org.
Not so much different from the previous level, the password for the next level is stored inside a file.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see the level goal:
The password for the next level is stored in a file called spaces in this filename located in the home directory
You notice that the filename contains space, so to view the content of the file we need to surround it with double quote or single quote, or we can escape the space character using backslash.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTF Hacker101 Flag 1 - A Little Something to Get You Started</title>
      <link>/en/posts/ctf-hacker101-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 18:16:37 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/posts/ctf-hacker101-1/</guid>
      <description>Another challange I do while learning programming, this is episode 1 by the way.
You can visit hacker101 if you want to play it too.
I start the level and it redirected me to a website with white background and a paragraph which said:
Welcome to level 0. Enjoy your stay. Nothing out of ordinary here. So, I inspect the page and look at the source code. Seems normal. Until I take a look at the &amp;lt;style&amp;gt; tag and saw the following lines:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire Bandit 2</title>
      <link>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 18:03:42 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-2/</guid>
      <description>Continue to Level 2. Here is the level goal:
The password for the next level is stored in a file called - located in the home directory
I connected to the game server using the password from the previous level. The file needed to get the password for the next level is located at the home directory, so I just typed in:
cat ./- And the content get printed.
If I typed cat - the content inside - file won&amp;rsquo;t be printed since typing cat - means the cat command will read from standard input.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire Bandit 1</title>
      <link>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 19:23:27 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-1/</guid>
      <description>After getting the password from Level 0, I connected to Level 1.
Here is the level goal by the way.
The password for the next level is stored in a file called readme located in the home directory. Use this password to log into bandit1 using SSH. Whenever you find a password for a level, use SSH (on port 2220) to log into that level and continue the game.
This one is pretty straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OverTheWire Bandit 0</title>
      <link>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 17:29:28 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/en/posts/bandit-overthewire-0/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing Bandit wargames in overthewire website, while doing so I want to share my journey here.
First level, it&amp;rsquo;s Level 0. The goal is to connect to the game server using ssh. This one is pretty straightforward, the only obstacle here is knowing how to use ssh.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m in a linux machine, I can easily read the manpage for ssh command.
The instruction for Level 0 is the following:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
